Finding aid for Blanchard Family Papers, ca. 1835-ca. 2000
Bentley Historical Library
- Nathan A. Cobb
  - Personal
    - Biographical Materials
      - Birth certificate (copy), 1899 (Box 1)
      - Curricula vitae and published biographical information, 1905-1932 (Box 1)
      - Family correspondence, 1998 (Box 1)
      - Grist to the Mill (by Jane Sutherland), 2001 (Box 1)
        (A book exploring the role played by N. A. Cobb and others in the development of Australia's wheat agriculture)
      - Laudatory letters (includes excerpts), 1890s-1930 (Box 1)
      - "Nathan A. Cobb, Botanist and Zoologist: A Pioneer Scientist in Australia" (biography written by Frieda Cobb Blanchard)
        - Asa Gray Bulletin article, 1957 (Box 1)
        - Manuscript, 1954 (Box 1)
        - Notes, circa 1950s (Box 1)
        - Topical Files
          - Autobiographical information, circa 1900s (Box 1)
          - Bibliography of N. A. Cobb's work, circa 1950s (Box 1)
          - Biographies of N. A. Cobb, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
          - Bios (journal) correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
          - Butler, E. J., 1929-1933 (Box 1)
          - Cobb (Alice V.) recollections and notes, 1940s (Box 1)
          - Cobb family correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 1)
          - Proctor (Fred) correspondence with N. A. Cobb, 1878-1888 (Box 1)
          - Qualifications (from New South Wales Department of Agriculture), 1894 (Box 1)
          - Spencer public schools, 1954 (Box 1)
          - Wheat, 1890s; 1928 (Box 1)
          - Williston Seminary, 1883-1929 (Box 1)
          - Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI), circa 1950s (Box 1)
    - Bird observations
      - Various species, 1923-1924; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Blue jays, 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      (some correspondence may be of a technical or professional nature)
      - Adams, Arthur K. (grandson), 1929; 1931 (Box 1)
      - Adams, Dorothy Cobb (daughter), 1913-1931 (Box 1)
      - Anderson, H. C. L., 1904-1909 (Box 1)
      - Armsby, H. P., 1902-1907 (Box 1)
      - Atwater, W. O., 1902-1904 (Box 1)
      - Bell, Mr. and Mrs. Alexander Graham, 1908-1922 (Box 1)
        (includes correspondence with others related to the Bells' 1910 visit to Australia)
      - Bertrand, Christiane (French war orphan), 1919-1920; includes photographs (Box 1)
      - Bessey, C. E., 1904-1917 (Box 1)
      - Blanchard, Frank N. (son-in-law), 1925-1926 (Box 1)
      - Blanchard, Frieda Cobb (daughter), 1910-1930 (Box 1)
      - Boyden, W., 1903-1905 (Box 1)
      - Chambers, W. E., 1906-1923 (Box 1)
      - Cobb, Alice V. (wife), 1889-1910; 5 folders (Box 1)
      - Cobb, Jane (Bigelow) (mother), 1900-1924 (Box 2)
        (includes correspondence related to the estate of Jane Cobb)
      - Cobb, Margaret Vara (daughter), 1912-1931 (Box 2)
      - Cobb, Victor (son), 1909-1927 (Box 2)
      - Cobb family (various), 1909-1927 (Box 2)
      - Dean, W. S., 1912-1917 (Box 2)
      - De Man, J. G., 1908-1925 (Box 2)
      - Eaton, T. E. W., 1901-1907 (Box 2)
      - Farrer, William, 1900-1904 (Box 2)
      - Flashman, J., 1901-1907 (Box 2)
        (includes correspondence related to the interment of Roger Cobb)
      - Galloway, E., 1904-1917 (Box 2)
      - Grosse, E. W., 1898-1910 (Box 2)
      - Haynes, E., 1895-1915 (Box 2)
      - Hays, M. M., 1901-1907 (Box 2)
      - Henry, H. A., 1900-1907 (Box 2)
      - Hilgard, E. W., 1902-1916 (Box 2)
      - Lewton-Brain, L., 1907-1909 (Box 2)
      - Loeb, J., 1914-1918 (Box 2)
      - Mann, A., 1913-1930 (Box 2)
      - Plumb, C. S., 1900-1905 (Box 2)
      - Proctor, Fred (brother-in-law) and Alvara (niece), 1877-1908 (Box 2)
      - Ross, Ruth (Cobb) (daughter), 1921 (Box 2)
      - Russel, E. H., 1886-1907 (Box 2)
      - Sawyer, J. H., 1897-1905 (Box 2)
      - Seelye, L. C., 1892-1903 (Box 2)
      - Shelton, E. M., 1901-1911 (Box 2)
      - Steiner, G., 1911-1927 (Box 2)
      - Walters, M. J., 1918-1920 (Box 2)
      - Williston Seminary, 1912-1928 (Box 2)
      - Young, R. T., 1914-1921 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1877-1930 (Box 2)
    - Death
      - Laboratory inventory (posthumous) and correspondence related to the sale of items, 1932-1936 (Box 2)
      - Obituaries
        - Journals (various), 1932 (Box 2)
        - Newspapers (various), 1932 (Box 2)
      - Remembrances and tributes
        - Commonwealth Mycological Institute (UK), 1962 (Box 2)
        - An Introduction to Nematology (by M. B. Chitwood), 1938 (Box 2)
        - Nathan A. Cobb Nematology Foundation (Society of Nematologists), 1998-1999 (Box 2)
        - Nematodon in Verband met de Vruchbaarheid van de Grond (by Ira M. Oostenbrink), 1957 (Box 2)
        - Personal correspondence (with Cobb family), 1932-1934; 1944 (Box 2)
        - United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) Nematode Collection, 1990 (Box 2)
        - Other, 1960s (Box 2)
    - Education
      - Spencer (Mass.) High School, 1875; includes photographs (Box 2)
      - Worchester Polytechnic Institute
        - Courses
          - Botany, 1880 (Box 2)
          - Chemistry, circa 1880 (Box 2)
            (lecture notebooks and coursework)
          - Crystallography
            - "Miller's System of Crystallography", 1873; notebook (Box 2)
            - Mathematical equations and notes, circa 1880 (Box 2)
          - Literature (commonplace book), 1880 (Box 2)
          - Physics, 1880 (Box 2)
        - Grade reports, 1879-1881 (Box 2)
        - Thesis ("Mathematical Crystallography"), 1931 (Box 2)
          (reprint of 1881 manuscript, originally titled "Notes on Miller's Crystallography")
        - Commencement, 1881 (Box 2)
        - Post-Graduation
          - "Alumni Notes", circa 1890s (Box 2)
          - Correspondence, 1906-1931 (Box 2)
          - Fiftieth anniversary celebration, 1915 (Box 2)
      - University of Jena (Germany): Lab notebook, 1887-1888; includes sketches (Box 3)
    - Income tax statements
      - 1897-1905 (Box 3)
      - 1915-1925 (Box 3)
    - Journals
      (volumes include entries related to professional activities as well as various sketches and drawings)
      - "Literary Suggestions", undated (Box 3)
        (shared with A. V. Cobb)
      - 1876 (Box 3)
      - 1877-1879 (Box 3)
      - 1879 (Box 3)
      - 1880-1883, 4 volumes (Box 3)
      - 1887 (Box 3)
      - 1888-1890, 3 volumes (Box 3)
      - 1893-1894, 2 volumes (Box 3)
      - 1899-1900, 2 volumes (Box 3)
      - 1915 (Box 3)
    - Residences
      - Inventory of home contents, 1902 (Box 3)
      - List of residences (United States and Australia), circa 1900 (Box 3)
      - Real estate and insurance dealings, 1904-1928 (Box 3)
      - Relocation to Washington, D.C. from Honolulu, Hawaii, 1907 (Box 3)
    - Topical Files (A-F), circa 1900s (Box 3)
    - Travel
      - Notes, 1899 (Box 3)
      - Records and souvenirs, 1887-1889 (Box 3)
    - Writings
      - Occasional verses, undated (Box 3)
      - Story (cow and a buried horse), undated (Box 3)
    - Other
      - Card (personal), undated (Box 3)
      - Dietary restrictions (related to digestive issues), 1916; 1920 (Box 3)
      - Fingerprints, undated (Box 3)
      - Hour plan (daily agenda), undated (Box 3)
        (possible from Worcester Polytechnic Institute)
      - Library inventory (partial), circa 1932 (Box 3)
      - Passports, 1887; 1921 (Box 3)
      - Taytasac legal matter, undated (Box 3)
      - Tools and hardware estimate, 1909 (Box 3)
  - Professional
    - Williston Academy
      - Correspondence, 1884-1887 (Box 3)
      - Experiment records (flies), 1887 (Box 3)
      - Grade books, circa 1880s (Box 3)
      - Report to the Principal of Williston Seminary on the departments of Natural Science and Drawing, 1884 (Box 3)
    - Analytical chemistry estimates, 1883-1890 (Box 3)
      (private practice, from Easthampton, Mass. and Australia)
    - Letters of introduction (for N. A. Cobb's arrival in Australia), 1889 (Box 3)
    - Advertising (Waterbury watches), circa 1889 (Box 3)
      (written for Chipman importing, Australia)
    - New South Wales (NSW), Australia, Department of Mines and Agriculture
      - Administrative materials
        - Appointment, 1890 (Box 3)
        - Qualifications, circa 1903 (Box 3)
        - Resignation, 1905 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence
        - 1891-1900 (Box 3)
        - 1898-1899, letterpress book (Box 3)
        - 1901-1905 (Box 4)
        - 1903-1905 (Box 4)
          (related to search for a professional engagement in America)
      - Experiments and observations
        - Agriculture (apples, apricots, roses, etc.), circa 1900; includes sketches and (Box 4)
        - Nematodes and insects, circa 1900; includes sketches and drawings (Box 4)
        - Rainfall, circa 1902-1903 (Box 4)
          (correspondence related to studies)
      - Reports
        - Annual reports
          - 1891 (Box 4)
          - 1892 (Box 4)
          - 1897 (Box 4)
        - Grain elevators, circa 1901; includes photographs (Box 4)
        - "Pure Culture of Wheat", undated (Box 4)
        - Spring wheat, undated (Box 4)
        - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm and School, circa 1890s (Box 4)
      - Special Commission to the United States and Europe
        - Appointment, conditions, and related correspondence, 1898 (Box 4)
        - Travel materials, 1898-1901 (Box 4)
    - Hawaiian Sugar Planters' Association (HSPA) Experiment Station, Division of Pathology and Physiology
      - Annual report, 1907 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1905-1907, 2 folders (Box 4)
          - 1907-1909 (Box 4)
            (post-employment; relates to publications and ongoing issues)
        - Dole, James D., 1907; includes photograph (Box 4)
        - Gifford, W. M. (Chairman, Special Commission on HSPA Experiment Station), 1904-1909 (Box 4)
      - Departmental personnel, 1905 (Box 4)
      - Laboratory design and sketches, undated (Box 4)
        (plans may relate to laboratory facilities elsewhere)
      - "Proceedings of the 26th Annual Meeting of the HSPA", 1906 (Box 4)
    - United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) Bureau of Plant Industry
      - Administrative materials
        - Appointments, 1907-1931 (Box 4)
        - Annual review questionnaire, undated (Box 4)
        - Bureau of Plant Industry proposed reorganization, 1911 (Box 4)
        - Bureau of Plant Industry salaries and length of service, 1910 (Box 4)
        - Efficiency rating, 1925 (Box 4)
        - Employment examination and qualifications, 1907 (Box 4)
        - USDA department ratings, circa 1925 (Box 4)
      - Award (National Association of Cotton Manufacturers' medal), 1916; includes photograph (Box 4)
      - Business card (N. A. Cobb), undated (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, 1908-1932; 9 folders (Box 4)
      - Nematology
        - Dissertation committees and examinations, 1915-1930 (Box 4)
        - Research materials (various), circa 1920s; includes sketch (Box 4)
        - Reports
          - "Mermis Albicans: A Nema Parasite of Grasshoppers and Other Insects", undated (Box 4)
          - "Scientific Studies of the Morphology and Physiology of Nemas", circa 1924 (Box 4)
      - Travel
        - Jamaica, 1909-1910 (Box 4)
        - Panama, 1921-1923 (Box 4)
    - Organizations
      - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1905-1910 (Box 4)
      - American Microscopical Society, 1915-1916 (Box 4)
      - Cosmos Club, 1909-1915 (Box 4)
      - Linnaean Society of New South Wales (NSW), Australia
        - Correspondence, 1894-1907 (Box 4)
        - Proceedings ("Australian Free-Living Marine Nematodes"), 1898 (Box 4)
      - National Geographic Society
        - Banquet, 1914 (Box 4)
        - Election, 1908 (Box 4)
      - Washington Academy of Sciences
        - Membership, 1918 (Box 5)
        - Presidency, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
          (correspondence related to N. A. Cobb's election and administration)
        - Retirement address, 1932 (Box 5)
      - Other, 1909-1925 (Box 5)
    - Speaking engagements
      - Advertisements and flyers, 1908-1929 (Box 5)
      - Transcripts and prepared remarks, circa 1900s-1930s (Box 5)
    - Writings: scientific methods related to nematology, use of microscopes, and other matters, undated (Box 5)
  - Publications
    - Catalog and annotated bibliography of N. A. Cobb's publications, circa 1930s (Box 5)
    - Collected works
      - Bulletins on Fungus Maladies of the Sugar Cane, circa 1908 (Box 5)
      - Bulletins on Tropical Agriculture, circa 1908 (Box 5)
      - Contributions to a Science of Nematology
        - Anthology of Nos. I-XVIII, circa 1930 (Box 5)
        - Correspondence
          - 1914 (Box 5)
          - 1932-1939, 2 folders (Box 5)
          - 1990 (Box 5)
        - Illustrations, undated (Box 5)
        - Individual papers
          - "A Key to the Genera of Free-Living Nemas", 1935 (Box 5)
          - Number 8 (acknowledgments), circa 1920 (Box 5)
          - Number 10 (manuscript), 1920 (Box 5)
          - Number 15 (correspondence), 1925 (Box 5)
        - Review, 1937 (Box 5)
        - Table of Contents (expanded version), circa 1935 (Box 5)
      - Diseases of Sugar Cane and Pineapple (with Microscope Installation), circa 1908 (Box 5)
      - Nema Papers, circa 1930s (Box 6)
      - Papers
        - Plant Pathology (Volume 1), circa 1940s (Box 6)
        - Wheat and Cotton (Volume 2), circa 1940s (Box 6)
        - Sugar Cane (Volume 3), circa 1940s (Box 6)
        - Free-Living Nemas and Parasites (Volume 4), circa 1940s (Box 6)
        - Nematology (Volume 5), circa 1940s (Box 6)
      - Plant Pathology and Other Papers, circa 1930s (Box 7)
    - Correspondence
      - Fresh water biology manual, 1912-1914 (Box 7)
      - Inquiries about N. A. Cobb's publications, 1934-1966 (Box 7)
      - Printing, page proofs, and related issues, 1912-1930 (Box 7)
    - Conference and meeting proceedings
      - Cambridge Philosophical Society, 1904 (Box 7)
      - National Association of Cotton Manufacturers, 1915 (Box 7)
    - Journals
      - Agricultural Gazette of New South Wales
        - Collected issues (Volume II), 1891 (Box 7)
        - "Letters on the Diseases of Plants" (dust jacket only), 1897 (Box 7)
        - "The Californian Wheat Industry", 1901; includes photographs used in the article's publication (Box 7)
        - Collected reports of N. A. Cobb, 1890-1903 (Box 7)
        - Various, 1890-1903 (Box 7)
      - The Collecting Net, 1931 (Box 8)
      - Journal of Agricultural Research, 1914-1923 (Box 8)
      - Journal of the American Medical Association, 1932 (Box 8)
      - Journal of Parasitology, 1914-1933 (Box 8)
      - Journal of the Washington Academy of Science, 1912-1932 (Box 8)
      - National Geographic Magazine, 1908-1932; includes photographs (Box 8)
      - Science, 1916-1931 (Box 8)
      - The Town and Country Journal, 1894 (Box 8)
      - Yearbook of the Department of Agriculture, 1914 (Box 8)
    - Nematodes, Mostly Australian and Fijian, 1893 (Box 8)
    - Yearbooks: compilations of yearly work that include drawings, sketches and original research
      - 1884-1887, 3 volumes (Box 8)
      - 1889-1893, 2 volumes (Box 8)
      - 1896-1898 (Box 8)
      - Yearbook and Experiment Station Reports of the HSPA, 1906 (Box 8)
    - Other
      - "The Apotheosis of the Blickensderfer" (poem and advertisement), 1902 (Box 9)
      - Book publishing agreement (for book on nematology), 1931 (Box 9)
      - Copyright notice for Elements of Chemistry, 1885 (Box 9)
      - Memorandum to printer in connection with an article on Draconema, undated (Box 9)
      - "Sugar Cane" (encyclopedia entry), undated (Box 9)
  - Inventions and Patents
    - Card index, 1915 (Box 9)
    - Cylinder calendar, undated (Box 9)
    - Microscope, mechanical stage, 1912-1918 (Box 9)
    - Microscope centering substages, 1918 (Box 9)
    - Microscope cover glass centering devices, 1912-1915 (Box 9)
    - Microscope finder slides, 1912-1920 (Box 9)
    - Microscope slides, 1912-1917 (Box 9)
    - Microscope slide case, 1917 (Box 9)
    - Microscope superfine adjustments, 1917 (Box 9)
    - Photographic camera
      - Shutters, chassis, plate holder, etc., 1899-1900 (Box 9)
        (includes sketches, descriptions, and patents granted)
      - Correspondence related to legal cases and royalties, 1901-1913 (Box 9)
    - Rifle sights, undated (Box 9)
    - Seed drill, 1899-1900 (Box 9)
    - Textile fibers (method and apparatus for determining mean or average length), 1916-1918 (Box 9)
    - Other, 1917-1918 (Box 9)
  - Clippings
    - Undated (Box 9)
    - 1884 (Box 9)
    - 1886 (Box 9)
    - 1887 (Box 9)
    - 1890 (Box 9)
    - 1893 (Box 9)
    - 1895-1897, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Crows (in Australia), 1890s (Box 9)
      (content related to N. A. Cobb's advocacy for the preservation of crows)
    - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm and School, New South Wales, Australia, 1890s (Box 9)
    - 1890s-1900s (Box 9)
    - 1898-1900 (Box 9)
      (content related to N. A. Cobb's service as Special Commissioner to the United States and Europe for the NSW Department of Mines and Agriculture)
    - 1901-1907, 7 folders (Box 9)
    - 1910-1911, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1913-1914, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1916 (Box 9)
    - 1918 (Box 9)
    - 1920s (Box 9)
    - 1924-1932, 8 folders (Box 9)
      (one clipping from 1931 is included in an oversize folder)
  - Visual Materials
    - Related written material
      - Correspondence
        - Adams, Charles A. (in regards to the use and purchase of solar cameras), 1901-1910 (Box 9)
        - General (in regards to photographic techniques, equipment (and the purchase thereof), and endeavors), 1900-1906 (Box 9)
      - Notes
        - Preparation of drawings and photographs for publication, undated; includes photographs and sketches (Box 9)
        - Photographic experiments (written record), undated (Box 9)
        - Photographic techniques, undated (Box 9)
    - Drawings and sketches
      (additional materials found throughout the collection as noted)
      - Agricultural scene (cotton?),undated (Box 9)
        (possibly drawn by E. M. Grosse)
      - Bathurst Experimental Farm residence floor plans, 1891 (Box 9)
      - Nematodes
        - Australian species, circa 1890s (Box 9)
        - Draft of advertisement for speaking engagement, circa 1910s (Box 9)
      - "Parapseudophacochoerostrongyloides", 1930 (Box 9)
        (humorous illustration for meeting materials of the Helminthological Society of Washington)
      - Plants and landscapes (various), undated (Box 9)
        (photographic reproductions)
      - Self-portrait and plants, circa 1890s (Box 9)
      - Sketchbook (includes nematodes, insects, plants, etc.), undated (Box 9)
    - Line engravings
      - Cobb, N. A., circa 1890s (Box 9)
        (rice paper page proof)
      - Illustration for unidentified publication, circa 1890s (Box 9)
        (reproduction)
    - Lithographic prints
      - Nematology cover image, circa 1910s (Box 9)
        (monographs privately published by Cobb and collected as Contributions to a Science of Nematology)
      - Plant pathologies (various images), undated (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9)
    - Negatives, film
      - Birdhouses, circa 1920 (Box 9)
      - Camp kitchen (Australia, possibly at Bong Bong), circa 1890s (Box 9)
      - Grasshoppers, circa 1920 (Box 9)
      - Laboratory interior (unidentified), undated (Box 9)
      - Photographic reproductions of Nathan and Alice Cobb's sketches, circa 1870s-1890s (Box 9)
      - Portraits
        - Cobb, Nathan, circa 1880s-1930s (Box 9)
        - Cobb (Nathan) and daughter, circa 1890s (Box 9)
        - Women (unidentified, probably Cobb family members), undated (Box 9)
    - Negatives, glass plate
      - 3" by 4", circa 1890-1910
        - Adelaide, South Australia, Australia
          - General, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Botanical gardens
            - Statues, 2 negatives (Box 10)
            - Victoria Regia (Box 10)
          - Horse car (Box 10)
          - Post office (Box 10)
          - Streetcars (Box 10)
          - Town hall and post office (Box 10)
          - Zoo
            - Birds (Box 10)
            - Deer (Box 10)
        - Aden (wreck of German warship) (Box 10)
        - Adobe Houses: Wagon Mound, New Mexico (Box 10)
        - Aecidium (Box 10)
        - Agricultural Schools
          - Alnarps, Sweden, 4 negatives (Box 10)
          - Berlin, Germany (Box 10)
          - Copenhagen, Denmark (Box 10)
          - Jena, Germany
            - Campus views, 3 negatives (Box 10)
            - Cow (Box 10)
          - Reading, England (includes college and laboratory) (Box 10)
        - Alamo (interior): San Antonio, Texas (Box 10)
        - Alaska
          - Coast channels, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Douglas Island and Native American canoe (Box 10)
          - Douglas Island and Juneau (Box 10)
          - Ft. Wrangel, totem pole, 3 negatives (Box 10)
          - Juneau, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Glacier Bay (Box 10)
          - Sitka, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Sitka and Indians (Box 10)
            (multiple images on one plate)
          - Sitka Bay, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Skagway (Box 10)
          - Skagway Mountains and icebergs (Box 10)
          - Skagway River (Box 10)
        - Algiers, Algeria
          - Farm scenes (Box 10)
          - Market, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Street scenes, 7 negatives (Box 10)
          - Arab people
            - Plowing (Box 10)
            - Seated on donkey (Box 10)
            - South Algiers, in, 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Camels herded, south Algiers (Box 10)
          - Village of nomads (middle Algiers) (Box 10)
        - Alstonville, New South Wales, Australia (Box 10)
        - Anderson, Guthries and Oliffe, Messrs. (Box 10)
        - Anderson and Shelton, Messrs. (Box 10)
        - Anderson's residence: Blue Mountains, New South Wales, Australia, 4 negatives (Box 10)
        - Arc de Triomphe (Paris, France) (Box 10)
        - Arizona scenes: red desert and pine country (Box 10)
        - Arkansas River
          - Cotton plantation (Box 10)
          - Near Canon City, Colorado (Box 10)
          - Near Little Rock, Arkansas (Box 10)
          - Rocky Mountains near Monte Cristo, Colorado (Box 10)
        - Arkansas swamp; plantations at Kerr, clearing near Forrest City (Box 10)
          (multiple images on plate)
        - Ashland, Oregon (Box 10)
        - Auckland, New Zealand
          - Approach to piers (Box 10)
          - Mr. Farmer leaning on bow rail (Box 10)
          - Moana coaling (Box 10)
          - Mt. Eden (panoramic view), 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Pier (Box 10)
          - Pier (panoramic view), 2 negatives (Box 10)
          - Timber loggers, 3 negatives (Box 10)
          - Union Company's wharf (view upon leaving), 2 negatives (Box 10)
        - Auction: Dea Practa place, 2 negatives (Box 10)
        - Austermere, New South Wales, Australia (Box 10)
        - Bahamas
          - Carriage with people (Box 10)
          - Houses (Box 10)
          - Landscape (Box 10)
          - Mule train (Box 10)
          - Trestle (Box 10)
        - Baldwin family place, 2 negatives (Box 10)
        - Barley grain, cross section (Box 10)
        - Barre rocking stove (Box 10)
        - Beal Combine Harvester (Duncan, owner) Stockton California (Box 10)
        - Bee Farm: New South Wales, Australia (between Tweed & Richmond Rivers) (Box 10)
        - Beet Sugar Mills: Salinas, California (Box 10)
        - "Best" Steam Draft Combine Harvester, 4 negatives (Box 10)
        - Big Stone Lake, South Dakota (Box 10)
        - Big Stone Lake and City, South Dakota (Box 10)
        - Bigelow Family (Groveport, Ohio) (Box 10)
        - Bigelow Family, (unidentified location; inscription on original envelope appears to be "Cherivalley") (Box 10)